Kontakt

www.linkedin.com/in/ stephanietoenjes (LinkedIn)

Top-Kenntnisse

Soziale Medien
Personal Branding
CEO Communications

Languages

Englisch (Professional Working)
Deutsch (Native or Bilingual)
Französisch (Elementary)

Certifications

Content Marketing Certified
Social Media Certified
Email Marketing Certified
Onlinemarketing (Google Garage)

Honors-Awards

PR Report Award in der Kategorie Social Media "Telekom goes TikTok"

Publications

Warum CEOs Social Media nutzen sollten

PR-Werkstatt: Wir PR-Profis die Fotoplattform optimal nutzen können. Ein Leitfaden.

Einfach nur peinlich

Ein Fazit zur CEBIT 2018

Stephanie Tönjes

Cluster Lead Social Media Deutsche Telekom | Personal Branding Coach | Founder #30xFriends

Zusammenfassung

Stephanie Tönjes is a Communications Expert and has been working in Corporate Communications at Deutsche Telekom for fifteen years. She's deeply passionate about digitization and everything that goes with it. New channels, new media: She's always been an early adopter and tries them all out! In addition, she is intensively focused on Personal Branding. Turning people into brands - that's what Stephanie really loves!

Berufserfahrung

Deutsche Telekom 16 Jahre 8 Monate

Cluster Lead Social Media @deutschetelekom Mai 2021 - Present (1 Jahr)

Bonn, Nordrhein-Westfalen, Deutschland

- strategic operation and coordination of all social media channels @deutschtelekom
- Member of the Management Team of Corporate Communitcations
- Member of the Telekom Social Media Board: strategic decision on establishing new social media accounts and closing existing accounts within the Group
- strategic development of digital channels and platforms
- coordination of cross-departmental topics, projects and campaigns
- establishing new social media channels like TikTok and Twitch
- developing new storytelling formats and content creation, especially for younger channels like TikTok

Digital Natives / Reverse Mentoring CEO Mai 2018 - Present (4 Jahre)

Bonn und Umgebung, Deutschland

As part of the selected digital natives of our CEO Tim Höttges, we present current trends and reflect current topics from the perspective of a younger generation. Tasks from this project include

- close cooperation with the CEO and his corporate office
- advice on special topics and strategies
- preparation and execution of CEO appearances at major events
- representation of management strategies and presentation of Deutsche Telekom at events
- Discussion and advice on digital trends
- Presentation of promising apps and startups
- Assessment of current business-relevant topics from the perspective of Generation Y
- Development of (solution) concepts on selected topics
- Supporting the CEO's public participation in close cooperation and coordination with the technical and corporate offices

as well as, transferring the vision of the program to the other areas of Deutsche Telekom and making it clear how important intergenerational exchange is.

Senior Communications Manager, Corporate Communications September 2017 - April 2021 (3 Jahre 8 Monate)

Bonn, Nordrhein-Westfalen, Deutschland

- Head of Social Media for @deutschetelekom channels
- strategic development of digital channels and platforms
- initializing and coordination of online projects
- supporting corporate divisions regarding cross-media communication projects
- trendscouting: constantly looking for new developments in the digital media world
- profound assessment of the use of new formats in the communication mix
- developing new storytelling formats as well as the integration of new digital tools and workflows
- contact management and work with bloggers and digital influencers

Junior Communications Manager, Corporate Communications Oktober 2006 - August 2017 (10 Jahre 11 Monate)

Bonn, Nordrhein-Westfalen, Deutschland

Marketing Manager Telekom Wholesale & IPF process September 2005 - September 2006 (1 Jahr 1 Monat)

Bonn, Nordrhein-Westfalen, Deutschland

#30xFriends

Founder des Social Media-Netzwerks & Podcast-Host #30xFriends September 2020 - Present (1 Jahr 8 Monate)

Das Netzwerk #30xFriends richtet sich an SocialMedia-Expert*innen, Freigeister und Pioniere. In einem ausgewählten Kreis diskutieren wir über aktuelle Social Media-Trends, tauschen Erfahrungen aus und wachsen zu einer starken Community zusammen. Zudem schauen wir uns Best- und Worst Cases an, tauchen ein in neue Kanäle und diskutieren, wie wichtig z. B. die Macht der Sprache im Umfeld von jungen Zielgruppen ist.

Regelmäßig werden wir exklusive Impulsgeber, Content Creator und Vordenker einladen, um von den Besten zu lernen.

Unser Anspruch
Wir definieren Social Media neu.
Wir sind immer einen Schritt voraus.
Wir glauben an die Macht von organischem Content.
Community First.

www.iherzfood.com Foodblogger iHERZfood Juni 2012 - Januar 2021 (8 Jahre 8 Monate)

T-Systems International GmbH Business Support Manager / MediaBroadcast Juni 2002 - August 2005 (3 Jahre 3 Monate)

Deutsche Telekom Management Assistant in Office Communication September 1999 - Mai 2002 (2 Jahre 9 Monate) Köln, Nordrhein-Westfalen, Deutschland

Education

Ausbildung

Berufskolleg an der Lindenstraße Köln Kauffrau für Bürokommunikation · (September 1999 - Mai 2002)